bencarson.com 2016-05-29

# Privacy Policy | Official Site Dr. Ben Carson

**Last Revised June 26, 2015**

Welcome to the website of Carson America, Inc. (“Carson America”), official website for the 2016 Presidential Campaign of Dr. Ben Carson. Carson America knows your right to privacy is important, especially online. This Privacy Policy has been created to answer questions you may have regarding Carson America’s data collection and protection policies. This Privacy Policy applies to information we collect when you use our websites, mobile sites, mobile applications and other online services that link to this Privacy Policy.

**What information is being collected at[www.bencarson.com](https://www.bencarson.com/?__hstc=34878590.11cb516680095f40b4a49655a0398d75.1435149860043.1435610059949.1435621070538.12&__hssc=34878590.11.1435621070538&__hsfp=1863559887)?**

The only personal information collected is information you give us. You do not have to provide this information in order to navigate the website. We only ask that provide the information so that we can better communicate with you. In an effort to grow our grassroots community online, Carson America may ask you to submit information.

By law, some information must be collected when you make a contribution. When you make contributions to Carson America that aggregate to more than $200, federal law requires us to use our “best efforts” to collect your name, mailing address, employer, and occupation. Credit card information provided may be stored at the donor’s option. In the event a donor exercises that option, all credit card information will be stored with Carson America’s secure, third-party vendor, certified to PCI Service Provider Level 1, the most stringent level of certification. Any information shared is done at the donor’s own risk.

We ask that anyone under 18 years of age not submit their information. In addition, in accordance with the Federal Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), Carson America does not knowingly collect personal identifiable information from persons 13 years of age or younger.

Our servers also collect certain server log information about your use of the website. This may include the type of browser you use, access times, pages viewed, your IP address, and the page you visited before navigating to our website.

**How is the information collected at[www.bencarson.com](https://www.bencarson.com/?__hstc=34878590.11cb516680095f40b4a49655a0398d75.1435149860043.1435610059949.1435621070538.12&__hssc=34878590.11.1435621070538&__hsfp=1863559887) used?**

The information that you voluntarily submit will be used by Carson America to provide you with information about Dr. Carson’s personal appearances, television appearances, talking points, and other related information. Additionally, when you offer your personal information or choose to participate in our volunteer efforts, we use your information to personalize and customize website pages and emails from Carson America to you. We may also use the information to credit individuals for their actions in support of Carson America, Dr. Carson and other Republican candidates. We are thankful for your support, and we want to recognize you.

Carson America may share information that you voluntarily provide us with like-minded organizations committed to the principles or candidates of the Republican Party, Republican State Party organizations and local Republican groups. Carson America may provide your email address or other personal information to authorized third parties required to deliver a particular service. These third parties may not use information we provide for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for Carson America.

**Is my information secure?**

Protecting information you provide is important to us. Carson America makes every effort to protect your information from the moment you enter your information to when it is stored on our secure servers. Carson America uses a secure socket layer (SSL) with the highest level of encryption commercially available for [www.bencarson.com](https://www.bencarson.com/?__hstc=34878590.11cb516680095f40b4a49655a0398d75.1435149860043.1435610059949.1435621070538.12&__hssc=34878590.11.1435621070538&__hsfp=1863559887) on pages where online visitors register or make a secure online donation using their credit card. Strict security measures are in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of any information on or collected through [www.bencarson.com](https://www.bencarson.com/?__hstc=34878590.11cb516680095f40b4a49655a0398d75.1435149860043.1435610059949.1435621070538.12&__hssc=34878590.11.1435621070538&__hsfp=1863559887). Carson America uses a secured/encrypted server for online credit card donations made through [www.bencarson.com](https://www.bencarson.com/?__hstc=34878590.11cb516680095f40b4a49655a0398d75.1435149860043.1435610059949.1435621070538.12&__hssc=34878590.11.1435621070538&__hsfp=1863559887). The online contribution form is in compliance with Federal Election Commission regulations. Carson America has appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to prevent unauthorized access.

[www.bencarson.com](https://www.bencarson.com/?__hstc=34878590.11cb516680095f40b4a49655a0398d75.1435149860043.1435610059949.1435621070538.12&__hssc=34878590.11.1435621070538&__hsfp=1863559887) may link to other websites. Our website may contain links to other websites and servers. Carson America does not bear responsibility for privacy policies or content on linked websites. Carson America has no control over the websites we link to. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on each website you visit. Carson America provides links to original articles written and maintained by third parties. These links are provided as a convenience and do not imply a claim of ownership in that content.

**How do I contact Carson America?**

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns, please contact Carson America by e-mail at [SocialMedia@CarsonHQ.com](mailto:SocialMedia@CarsonHQ.com).

**Will this privacy policy change?**

We have no intentions to make changes to this Privacy Policy, though we do reserve the right to revise or update this Privacy Policy at any time. If we do make a change, we will revise the date at the top of the Privacy Policy.

**3rd Party Advertising Cookies Opt-Out**

Carson America is dedicated to providing privacy on the Internet. In addition to developing our Privacy Policy, we have provided you the opportunity to opt out of future 3rd party advertising cookies.

Carson America or a data provider Carson America has engaged may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser to enable you to receive customized advertising or content. Cookies placed on your browser by Carson America contain no personally identifiable information. The cookies may reflect de-identified demographic or other data linked to data you voluntarily have submitted to us (e.g., your email address) that we may share with a data provider solely in hashed, non-human readable form.

This Privacy Policy does not cover the collection methods or use of the information collected by vendors of Carson America. These vendors have their own privacy policies and may be members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) or the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAI”). To remove yourself from some or all NAI or DAI member advertising programs, please visit the DAI Opt-Out Page at <http://www.aboutads.info/choices> and follow the relevant instructions. Please note that if you delete, block, or otherwise restrict cookies, or if you use a different computer or Internet browser, you may need to renew your opt-out choice.
